CURRICULUM VITAE

Syed Khaja Nizamuddin.

S/O Syed Khaja Mazher Uddin.

H.No: 1-4-308/21/12/A
Bholakpur Musheerabad,
Gangaputra Sangam.
Email Id: Syed.khaja.Nizamuddin93@gmail.com

Hyderabad-500080. Mobile no: +917416259822

916301569921

CAREER OBJECTIVES:

To associate myself with an organization, this gives me an adequate opportunity to display my knowledge and professional skills in the chosen profession through continuous learning and development. I would like to enhance the growth of the organization, if given an opportunity I will put in my best effort with full enthusiasm and accomplish the task given to me on time with quality.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

Holding 63 Months of experience in US Health Care Industry with covering aspects of medical billing, Postings and AR Management through the Eligibility check to claims denial management, RCM. Expert in dealing all the Federal and Commercial payer like Medicare, Medicaid Etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Inventurus Knowledge Solutions (Senior Process Executive) (June-2016 – Aug2018) Wipro Pvt limited Company Healthcare (Senior Process Executive) (Aug 2018 – March 2022)

Company Profile:

Inventurus Knowledge Solutions, Inc. Provides an integrated solution that enables enterprise to achieve financial and profitable outcomes. It offers IKS MARGIN that increases revenue and collections, as well as decreases costs and expands margins. The company also provides a suite of services to optimize the technology for clinicians and staff to run the practice and provide care. Inventurus Knowledge Solutions, Inc. was founded in 2006 and is based in New York, NY.

Wipro Pvt Limited Company. Wipro is an Indian multinational corporation that provides Bangalore, Karnataka, India.in 2013.

Job Responsibilities:

- Doing AR follow-up with Insurance companies on call.
- ➤ Posting the denials based the response received on call/web/remits.
- > Final resolution to the claims pending in terms of Adjustment/Payment.
- Submit the pending claims to insurance post verifying/resolving the EDI rejection.

Key Responsibilities as an AR:

Placing outbound calls to the Insurance companies and verifying patients' insurance coverage and billing the respective insurance. Sorting out the issues associated with the policy plans and making required modifications to the claim and refilling them.

Worked as an A/R representative for 43 months and having good experience in dealing with federal payers like Medicare, Medicaid and Commercial Insurances.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- ➤ Joined as a Process Trainee Associate and promoted as Process Associate within six months of joining.
- ➤ Consistently maintained 99% accuracy and met desired results keeping commitments with good overall ratings.
- Rewarded with the Rising Star within 4 months of joining with Wipro
- Achieved Spot Light award, Unicorn award and the best performer's award for maintaining the quality by 97%.

Educational Qualifications:

- Completed Graduation (B.com (Computers)) from St. Paul's Degree College, affiliated to Osmania University, Hyderabad during 2013-2016.
- Completed Intermediate (C.E.C) from Rishi Junior College, affiliated to Board of Intermediate Education, Hyderabad during 2011-2012.
- ➤ Completed Schooling from Queens High School, affiliated to Secondary School Certificate Education, Hyderabad 2011.

Software Exposure:

Client Software's : Next Gen, MD4.

Operating systems: Win 2003, Win XP, Win 7, 8 and 10.

Packages : Ms-Office.

Personal Details:

Name : SYED KHAJA NIZAMUDDIN

Date of Birth : 25^t AUGUST 1993

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian

Degree college :. St Paul's Degree and pg college

Year of passing. :. 2016 passout

Cont No :. 7416259822

Marital Status : Single

Languages known : English, Hindi, Urdu and Telugu.

Permanent Address : Hno: 1-4-308/21/12/A Bholakpur Musheerabad

Gangaputra Sangam Hyderabad 500 080. TS

DECLARATION.

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Place:	
Date:	(SYED KHAJA NIZAMUDDIN)